# ENRIQUE SANTIBÁÑEZ CORTÉS

Street 16 September #12 CP: 62715, Tlayecac, Morelos, Mexico. <a href="mailto:enriquesec@gmail.com">enriquesec@gmail.com</a> · Phone number: (+52)-612-169-7320 LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/3lhCsl2, Github: https://bit.ly/3BTm5Y6

I am a master's student, wanting to learn more every day. With one year of experience as a Data Scientist. I have extra computer knowledge with the help of the online platform Coursera, DataCamp and EDX with more than 40 scientific events with topics related to Statistics, Mathematics and/or Computation.

## WORK HISTORY

**JANUARY 2022-PRESENT** 

### **INTERNSHIP MASTER, KANTAR**

Considering the NBD-Dirichlet model which is a mixture of 4-phase distributions, analyze the consumer's purchasing behavior, focusing on studying the value of brands.

### **SEPTEMBER 2019-AUGUST 2020**

# **DATA SCIENCE, OPI ANALYTICS**

Opi Analytics is a Mexican company that develops technological tools for data analysis for decision-making. During the work period I have built ETLs, analyze different sources of information to make sales predictions, estimate the effect caused by different events (new launches, promotions, etc.), and make geographical indicators.

JUNE, 2019 - AUGUST, 2019

### INVESTIGATOR, INSTITUTE OF SOCIAL INVESTIGATIONS, UNAM.

Incorporated in one of the current research projects of Dr. Judith Zubieta García, in which her knowledge of Statistics was used to conclude the analysis of the information

# **EDUCATION**

**AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT** 

# MASTER'S DEGREE IN STATISTICAL COMPUTING, CENTER FOR RESEARCH IN MATHEMATICS. MEXICO.

Thesis: BO-TextAutoAugment Data augmentation automatic in NLP using Bayesian Optimization. Assistant in two master's courses related to Data Science. **2015-2019** 

# BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: STATISTICS, AUTONOMOUS UNIVERSITY OF CHAPINGO

Thesis: Estimation of Mexico's income using Phase-Type distributions.

### **APTITUDES**

- Strong knowledge of statistics and deep learning (DEL, NLP).
- Advanced/intermediate programming, R and Python.
- Work experience: PBI, Amazon platform (EC2), Azure (Data Bricks, Data Factory), Spark (pyspark), Git and use of Docker containers.
- Office y LaTeX.
- Eager to learn, initiative.

# PARTICIPATIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS (LAST 3 YEARS)

- 1. 15° Industrial Problem Solving Workshop, CIMAT. (2022)
- 2. Winner of the SAS LATAM 2021 scholarship, SAS Institute. (2021)
- 3. 14° Industrial Problem Solving Workshop, CIMAT. (2021)
- 4. XIX School of Probability, and Statistics, CIMAT. (2021)
- 5. Mexican workshop on data science and big data, CIMAT. (2020)
- 6. 1st School of Distributed Algorithms and Parallel Algorithms, CIMAT. (2020)
- 7. Summer School Natural Language Processing (2020).
- 8. Summer of scientific research, AMC. (2019)
- 9. XVII School of Probability, and Statistics, CIMAT. (2019)
- 10. Workshop on inference and quantification of uncertainty in problems in science and engineering, UNAM. (2019)

### CERTIFICATIONS

### **EDX**

• MICROMASTER OF STATISTICS AND DATA SCIENCE 40% (2 CURSOS)

### **DATACAMP**

- PYTHON PROGRAMMER 100% (15 CURSOS)
- DATA ANALYST WITH PYTHON 100% (6 CURSOS)
- MACHINE LEARNING SCIENTIST WITH PYTHON 23% (3 CURSOS)
- BIG DATA WITH PYTHON 86% (5 CURSOS)
- DATA ANALYST WITH R 58% (13 CURSOS)

### **COURSERA**

### SPECIALIZATION:

- Python for everyone 60% (3 cursos)
- Introduction to Data Science 75% (3 cursos)
- Practical Predictive Analytics: Models and Methods, online Coursera. (2021)
- Bayesian Statistics: From Concept to Data Analysis, online Coursera. (2020)
- Neutral Networks and Deep Learning, Deeplearning, online Coursera. (2019)
- Python for Data Science. International Business Machines (IBM), online Coursera. (2018)
- Introduction to Data Science in Python. University of Michigan, online Coursera. (2018)